ERIK KIMSEY

// SOFTWARE ENGINEER

erikkimsey.com

T: 540 278 4525 E: kimseyerik@gmail.com As a software engineer and creative technologist, I seek the best tools and architecture for the job. My passions lay in creating beautiful, exciting, intuitive, performant, and innovative experiences with high-technology. ...Or, any technology.

github.com/erikkimsey linkedin.com/in/erikkimsey

SKILLS

Full-Stack Engineering

- · JavaScript, ReactJS,
- P5.js
- · React-Native
- · CSS3 / Sass / CSS-in-JS
- HTML5
- Unity3D
- Blender
- NodeJS / Express
- GraphQL / Apollo
- · Python / Django
- Webpack
- Bootstrap 4
- · Web Audio, Web Sensor APIs
- D3.js
- Angular

Languages

- Javascript (ES6/7)
- · C# (Unity3D)
- Python
- SQL
- GraphQL
- Java (Android)
- Processing
- · C/C++

Design Tools

- Adobe Illustrator
- · Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe InDesign
- Adobe XD

Misc. Technology

- Android SDK
- Propellerhead Reason
- Abelton Live
- Audacity
- Blender
- Arduino / IC
- JUCE
- Adobe Premiere
- · Adobe AfterEffects

WORK EXPERIENCE

09/2019 - 11/2019 CHATWISE

Full-Stack Engineer (Contract) (ReactJS, Node/Express, Postgres, ngrok, & Messenger API)

 Using the Facebook Messenger API, Postgres, and React, developed a dynamic chatbot that provides Blinkist-type functionality within Messenger.

06/2019 - 09/2019

THE REALM

React-Native Engineer (Contract) (React-Native, Redux, ES6, Figma)

 Within React-Native, I contributed to architecting and developing the Realm gamer-focused marketplace and social-media app.

3/2019 - 06/2019 CONNECT OUR KIDS

React-Native Engineer (Contract) (React-Native, Styled-Components)

 Contributed to the development of Connect Our Kids first mobile app, using React-Native.

1/2018

RAINCROW

Back-End Engineer (Contract) (NodeJS & Redis)

Contributed to the early-stage engineering of a Node server and Redis database supporting the activity of a MMORPG (Covens)

10/2016 - 6/2017 CHARTIQ

JavaScript Engineer

(JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, & AngularJS)

- Helped implement "ProCharts" in a ChartIQ client's application
- Contributed to performance upgrades, using JavaScript, to ChartlQ's flagship financial-charting solution

EDUCATION

2018 - 2019 COMPUTER SCIENCE

Lambda School

Curriculum:

- Full-Stack Web Development
- Database and RESTful API Design
- Programming paradigms (Declarative, Imperative, and Procedural)
- · Software Design Patterns
- Single-Page Application Development
- · Algorithm Analysis
- Data Structures
- · Theory of Computation
- Computer Architecture
- Cellular Automata
- Version Control
- Agile (Scrum and Kanban) and Waterfall techniques

8/2017 - 12/2017 COMPUTER SCIENCE

OSU

- Object-Oriented Programming in C++
- Discrete Maths

2012

WEB DESIGN & DEVELOPMENT (CERT)

Blue Ridge Community College

- Javascript, HTML, CSS, Java
- · Graphic Design Concepts
- Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign

2006 - 2010 PHILOSOPHY (BS)

James Madison University
Minors: creative writing & design

- Phi Sigma Tau Philosophy Honors Society Member
- Director of the Club of Creative Writing